Finding Aid for G. Mennen Williams Papers
Bentley Historical Library
- Non-Gubernatorial Papers
  - Michigan Supreme Court, 1970-1988
    - Correspondence
      - Cranks, 1970-1986; 24 folders (Box 63-N)
    - People file, 1970-1986
      - Archer, Dennis, 1984-1985 (Box 64-N)
      - Belli, Melvin, 1975 (Box 64-N)
      - Bonner, Ray (re Philippines), 1985 (Box 64-N)
      - Bonner, Thomas (re Pat Eames), 1980 (Box 64-N)
      - Boyden, Joel, 1983-1984 (Box 64-N)
      - Boyle, Justice Patricia, 1983-1985 (Box 64-N)
      - Brickey, Justice James, 1983-1986 (Box 64-N)
      - Bronson, Jerome, 1986 (Box 64-N)
      - Bueno, Cunha (re Pat Negrao), 1982 (Box 64-N)
      - Cavanaugh, Justice Michael, 1983-1985 (Box 64-N)
      - Coleman, Justice Mary, 1973-1982 (Box 64-N)
      - Davis, Corbin, 1983-1985 (Box 64-N)
      - Erdman, Joseph (re Congo), 1976 (Box 64-N)
      - Farrell, Tom, 1985-1986 (Box 64-N)
      - Golden, Robert (re Michigan Bar), 1985 (Box 64-N)
      - Hall, Marilyn R., 1983-1986; 3 folders (Box 64-N)
      - Harriman, Averill, 1971-1983 (Box 64-N)
      - Hoag, Hal, 1974-1984; 4 folders (Box 64-N)
      - Holt, Robert T., 1980 (Box 64-N)
      - Horowitz, Aaron (re Staebler), 1983 (Box 64-N)
      - Kavanaugh, Justice Thomas, 1970-1985; 2 folders (Box 64-N)
      - Lane, Roger, 1983-1986 (Box 64-N)
      - Levin, Justice Charles, 1973-1985 (Box 64-N)
      - Lynch, A. L., 1983-1985 (Box 64-N)
      - Moody, Justice Blair, Jr., 1979-1982 (Box 64-N)
      - Moody, Blair, III, 1983 (Box 64-N)
      - Mikesell, Willard, 1975 (Box 64-N)
      - Naftaly, Robert, 1984 (Box 64-N)
      - Noer, Robert (re. Africa), 1980 (Box 64-N)
      - Payant, V. Robert, 1985-1986; 2 folders (Box 64-N)
      - Ravitz, Justin, 1983 (Box 64-N)
      - Riley, Justice Dorothy Comstock, 1983-1986 (Box 64-N)
      - Roark, Mayford, 1982-1985 (Box 64-N)
      - Ryan, Justice James, 1976-1986 (Box 64-N)
      - Stroh, Nicholas, 1971-1972 (Box 64-N)
      - Tobin, James (re Blair Moody), 1979 (Box 64-N)
      - Walsh, Dan, 1984 (Box 64-N)
      - Willertz, Dan (re Phil Hart), 1978 (Box 64-N)
      - Williams, G. Mennen (memos), 1971-1986; 6 folders (Box 64-N)
      - Woodfill, W. Stuart, 1975-1979 (Box 64-N)
    - Topical Files, 1971-1988
      - Abortion, 1972 (Box 65-N)
      - Advisory Committee on Court Statistics, 1975-1977 (Box 65-N)
      - Alpena Family Court Project, 1977 (Box 65-N)
      - Amalgamated Department Store and Retail Employees, 1977 (Box 65-N)
      - Attorney Grievance Commission, 1986 (Box 65-N)
      - Campbell Competition Briefs, 1971 (Box 65-N)
      - Center for the Administration of Justice, 1972-1976 (Box 65-N)
      - Child Care/Support, 1979, 1986; 2 folders (Box 65-N)
      - Citizens Concern Committee, 1979-1980 (Box 65-N)
      - Comparative Negligence, 1980-1982 (Box 65-N)
      - Complaint Unit, 1975 (Box 65-N)
      - Court Housing, 1973-1975 (Box 65-N)
      - Crime Committee, 1976 (Box 65-N)
      - Criminal Statistics, 1977-1978 (Box 65-N)
      - Crisis in Prison Transport, 1985 (Box 65-N)
      - Department of Social Services, 1984-1986 (Box 65-N)
      - Detroit College of Law Review (GMW article), 1983 (Box 65-N)
      - Detroit Symphony, Musicians Bargaining, 1975-1976 (Box 65-N)
      - Disqualification of Supreme Court Justices, 1974-1975 (Box 65-N)
      - Employee Compensation, 1977-1979; 2 folders (Box 65-N)
      - Fair Court Housing, 1982-1983 (Box 65-N)
      - Interest on Lawyers' Trust Accounts, 1983-1986 (Box 65-N)
      - Judicial Liability Insurance, 1983-1984 (Box 65-N)
      - Judicial tenure, 1975-1979; 2 folders (Box 65-N)
      - Juris Grant, 1980-1981 (Box 65-N)
      - Landlord-Tenant, 1980-1983 (Box 65-N)
      - Mackinac Bridge Anniversary, 1983-1984 (Box 65-N)
      - Mediation Evaluation Committee, 1981 (Box 65-N)
      - Medical Malpractice, 1974-1975; 2 folders (Box 66-N)
      - Michigan Appellate Assigned Counsel System, 1985-1986 (Box 66-N)
      - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 66-N)
      - National Center for State Courts, 1972-1973 (Box 66-N)
      - Part-time Probate Judges Committee, 1983-1985 (Box 66-N)
      - Parochaid, 1971 (Box 66-N)
      - PBB Conference, 1978 (Box 66-N)
      - People Against Seafarer, 1978 (Box 66-N)
      - Princeton University, 1982 (Box 66-N)
      - "Program for Excellence", 1985 (Box 66-N)
      - Questionnaires, 1978 (Box 66-N)
      - Reapportionment, 1972; 1982; 2 folders (Box 66-N)
      - Resource Center for Consumers, 1975-1977 (Box 66-N)
      - Revision and Consolidation of Assignment Statutes, 1982-1983 (Box 66-N)
      - Sentencing, 1975-1986 (Box 66-N)
      - Standard Jury Instructions, 1983-1985 (Box 66-N)
      - State Appellate Defender Commission, 1983-1986 (Box 66-N)
      - State Bar Redistricting, 1985 (Box 66-N)
      - State Board of Legal Examiners, 1981-1984 (Box 66-N)
      - State of Michigan Legislative Committee, 1980 (Box 66-N)
      - Statistics, 1978-1981 (Box 66-N)
      - Supreme Court Classification Study, 1972 (Box 66-N)
      - Supreme Court Committee on State Bar Activities, 1984 (Box 66-N)
      - Supreme Court of Appeals Meeting, 1982 (Box 66-N)
      - Supreme Court Regulatory Authority, 1983 (Box 66-N)
      - Survey of Judicial Salaries, 1976-1979 (Box 66-N)
      - Systems Task Force, 1971 (Box 66-N)
      - University of North Africa, 1971-1972 (Box 66-N)
      - Videotaping, 1972-1984 (Box 66-N)
      - Wayne County Jail Crowding Problem, 1975 (Box 66-N)
      - Williams' Role on the Supreme Court, 1973 (Box 66-N)
      - Williams' Room Dedication, 1975 (Box 66-N)
      - Williams' Swearing-In Ceremony, 1979 (Box 66-N)
      - Women's Lawyers Association of Michigan, 1980-1986 (Box 66-N)
  - Political, 1960-1978
    Materials in the Political series detail Williams' activities in the state and national Democratic parties and provide excellent insight into his campaigns for political office after leaving the governorship. The twelve linear feet of papers in boxes 66-78 are arranged in a rough chronological order with the bulk of the materials relating to his campaigns for the Senate in 1966, and the Michigan Supreme Court in 1970 and 1978. The strength of this group resides in the 1966 Senatorial Election series. These materials provide a day-by-day, county-by-county, look at a consummate campaigner. The people files provide a glimpse into the grassroots organization of the Democratic party in Michigan. This series is nicely complemented by other collections in the Michigan Historical Collection especially the papers of Neil Staebler and Helen Berthelot, and the records of the Democratic Party (Michigan), State Central Committee. Material relating to Williams initial campaign for governor is located in box five and six of the Non-gubernatorial subgroup, while material on subsequent campaigns is located in the Governor's Papers subgroup. (see also boxes 5 and 6 for political materials)
    - Post-Gubernatorial Democratic Party, 1960-1965
      - Michigan, 1960-1965
        - Memos, 1960; 6 folders (Box 67-N)
        - Judge Starr Testimonial, 1960 (Box 67-N)
        - Campaigns (including Staebler), 1961-1962; 2 folders (Box 67-N)
        - Constitutional Convention (Williams' testimony), 1961-1962 (Box 67-N)
        - Michigan Taxes, 1963 (Box 67-N)
        - Operation 1964 (Box 67-N)
        - Campaigns, 1964; 5 folders (Box 67-N)
        - Public Works Project, 1964 (Box 67-N)
        - Campaigns, 1965 (Box 67-N)
      - National, 1962-1965
        - Campaigns, 1962-1963; 2 folders (Box 67-N)
        - Kennedy Funeral, 1963 (Box 67-N)
        - Kennedy Library, 1964 (Box 67-N)
        - Organization sponsorship, 1964; 2 folders (Box 68-N)
        - Platform, 1964; 2 folders (Box 68-N)
        - Democratic National Convention, 1964; 3 folders (Box 68-N)
        - Campaigns, 1964-1965; 3 folders (Box 68-N)
      - Nationalities Division, 1960-1964; 17 folders (Box 68-N)
    - Campaign for the Senate, 1965-1966
      - Administrative materials, 1965-1966
        - Correspondence, 1966; 10 folders (Box 69-N)
          (alphabetically by state)
        - Correspondence: GMW personal, 1965-1966; 8 folders (Box 69-N)
        - Media files, 20 folders (Box 69-N)
          (alphabetically by outlet)
        - Position papers, 1966; 11 folders (Box 69-N)
        - Press releases, 1966; 10 folders (Box 69-N)
        - Staff reports and memos, 1966; 33 folders (Box 70-N)
        - Surveys of the Political Climate in Michigan, June and October, 1966 (Box 70-N)
        - Trip files, 1966; 2 folders (Box 70-N)
      - County files, 1966 (Box 71-N)
        - A-O, 79 folders (Box 71-N)
        - P-W, 17 folders (Box 72-N)
      - Topical files, 1966 (Box 73-N)
        - A-E, 39 folders (Box 73-N)
        - F-P, 50 folders (Box 74-N)
        - R-Z, 33 folders (Box 75-N)
    - Interregnum Democratic Party, 1967-1970
      - People files, 1967-1970
        - Aybout, Saad (Box 76-N)
        - Burford, Jeremy (Box 76-N)
        - Burgett, Bill (Box 76-N)
        - Cohn, Avern (Box 76-N)
        - Emrich, Rev. Richard (Box 76-N)
        - Fleming, Robben (Box 76-N)
        - Galbraith, John Kenneth (Box 76-N)
        - Gilmore, Horace (Box 76-N)
        - Haber, William (Box 76-N)
        - Hare, James (Box 76-N)
        - Heller, Dr. William (Box 76-N)
        - Hutches, Rev. G. E. (Box 76-N)
        - Johnson, Lyndon Baines (Box 76-N)
        - Kaunda, Kenneth (Box 76-N)
        - Keith-Smith (Box 76-N)
        - King, Martin Luther, Jr. (Box 76-N)
        - Lamb, Betty (Box 76-N)
        - Langius, Gus (Box 76-N)
        - Levin, Sander (Box 76-N)
        - McCarthy, Eugene (Box 76-N)
        - McKenna, Mrs. Patrick A. (Box 76-N)
        - Matish, George and Ann (Box 76-N)
        - Milds, Hubert ("Father Jack") (Box 76-N)
        - Moody, Blair, Jr. (Box 76-N)
        - Palmer, Joseph, II (Box 76-N)
        - Price, Hickman (Box 76-N)
        - Robinson, Jim (Box 76-N)
        - Rockefeller, Hon. Nelson A. (Box 76-N)
        - Rossen, Jordan (Box 76-N)
        - Rusk, Dean (Box 76-N)
        - Shriver, Sargent (Box 76-N)
        - Staebler, Michael (Box 76-N)
        - Traynick, Dr. Leland E. (Box 76-N)
        - Truman, Harry S (Box 76-N)
        - Voelker, John D. (Box 76-N)
        - Warren, Dr. Donald T. (Box 76-N)
        - Wiener, Alexander L., Jr. (Box 76-N)
        - Williams, Emma M. (Box 76-N)
      - Topical files, 1967-1969; 22 folders (Box 76-N)
    - Supreme Court Election, 1970
      - Correspondence, 1970; 5 folders (Box 77-N)
      - County Breakdown, 1970 (Box 77-N)
      - Finances, 1970; 3 folders (Box 77-N)
      - Topical, 1970; 30 folders (Box 77-N)
      - Voter Analysis, 1970 (Box 77-N)
      - Williams' Trip Logs, 1970 (Box 77-N)
      - Miscellaneous, 1970; 3 folders (Box 77-N)
    - Supreme Court Election, 1978
      - Topical, 1978; 47 folders (Box 78-N)
  - Personal papers, 1883-1986; 1960-1986
    The materials in the Personal series run to 29 linear feet (boxes 79-107) and cover the years 1883 through 1988 with the bulk of the materials dealing with the last twenty- five years of Williams' life. The materials in this group are arranged by type and then chronologically.
    The Schedules subseries provides a near daily-description of his activities, and the Speeches series manifests his changing attitudes and roles as he moved from statesman to judge. An index of his speeches between 1971 and 1986 is in box 100. Of special interest in the Personal group are those familial papers not created by G. Mennen Williams, but which he preserved. These provide access to the perspectives of Williams' mother and father, and by reflection, show insight into G. Mennen himself. Finally, the personal papers of Nancy Quirk Williams illuminate her crucial roles as wife, mother, co-campaigner, and public liaison for G. Mennen Williams. Some personal material, such as Williams' school notebooks, is included in the Pregubernatorial series, see boxes 1-N - 3-N
    - Appointment Books
      - 1965-1968, 6 volumes (Box 78-N)
      - 1969-1986, 26 volumes (Box 79-N)
    - Correspondence, General, 1960-1987
      - 1960-1967, 27 folders (Box 81-N)
      - 1968-1971, 43 folders (Box 82-N)
      - 1972-1987, 22 folders (Box 83-N)
    - Family, 1883-1985; 1911-1975
      - Elma C. and Henry P. Williams, 1883-1963
        - Correspondence, 1906-1963; 15 folders (Box 84-N)
        - Financial, 1883-1963; 11 folders (Box 84-N)
        - Miscellaneous, 1911-1963; 4 folders, 3 volumes (Box 84-N)
      - Ketterers (Nancy and Ted), 1967-1985; 3 folders (Box 85-N)
      - Williams, Dick and Mollie, 1961-1965 (Box 85-N)
      - Williams, G. Mennen (personal), 1958-1967; 4 folders (Box 85-N)
      - Williams, Gery and Lannie, 1958-1967; 5 folders (Box 85-N)
      - Williams, Henry P., Jr., 1968-1985; 2 folders (Box 85-N)
      - Williams, Wendy, 1967-1971 (Box 85-N)
      - Williams family miscellaneous, 1957-1975; 15 folders, 3 folders (Box 85-N)
    - Financial, 1960-1965
      - Contributions/Donations, 1959-1965; 12 folders (Box 86-N)
      - Notes and memos, 1960-1963; 3 folders (Box 86-N)
    - Organizations (Charitable), 1967-1984
      - A-G, 48 folders (Box 87-N)
      - H-Z, 35 folders (Box 88-N)
      - University files, 1967-1984
        - A-Meharry, 8 folders (Box 88-N)
        - M-Z, 30 folders (Box 89-N)
    - People File, 1956-1986
      (see also box 64)
      - Abonyi, Malvina, 1984 (Box 90-N)
      - Adamany, David, 1983-1985 (Box 90-N)
      - Ayer, F. Cameron, 1977 (Box 90-N)
      - Berthelot, Helen, 1967-1987 (Box 90-N)
      - Blanchard, Gov. James, 1983-1986 (Box 90-N)
      - Bohlin, Einar, 1971-1985 (Box 90-N)
      - Bolen, Ambassador David, 1980 (Box 90-N)
      - Bowles, Chester, 1971 (Box 90-N)
      - Brown, Edmund G. (Pat), 1976-1985 (Box 90-N)
      - Browne, Ernest C., 1969 (Box 90-N)
      - Bryce, Dr. Edward, 1971 (Box 90-N)
      - Bundy, William P., 1969 (Box 90-N)
      - Burns, Wendy Williams, 1971-1986 (Box 90-N)
      - Crum, Frank, 1968-1969 (Box 90-N)
      - Cuzon, Fr. Roger, 1971 (Box 90-N)
      - De Groot, Roy Andreas, 1971 (Box 90-N)
      - Denison, James H., 1985 (Box 90-N)
      - De Zaba, Dr. Bob, 1978 (Box 90-N)
      - Diggs, Charles M., Jr., 1970 (Box 90-N)
      - Donahue, Paul M., 1967-1977 (Box 90-N)
      - Fredericks, J. Wayne, 1967-1984; 2 folders (Box 90-N)
      - Gilmore, Horace, 1970-1984; 2 folders (Box 90-N)
      - Gould, Wesley (re. Frank Gould), 1976 (Box 90-N)
      - Gram, Jim, 1966-1968 (Box 90-N)
      - Grano, Joseph, 1985-1986 (Box 90-N)
      - Griffiths, Hicks, 1972-1984 (Box 90-N)
      - Hale, S. C. Nate, 1977-1979 (Box 90-N)
      - Hare, James M., 1956-1968 (Box 90-N)
      - Harriman, Averill, 1970 (Box 90-N)
      - Hart, Adelaide, 1967-1982 (Box 90-N)
      - Hart, Sen. Philip, 1968-1974 (Box 90-N)
      - Hart, William R., 1971-1973 (Box 90-N)
      - Haughton, Ronald, 1967 (Box 90-N)
      - Henderson, A. B., 1970-1971 (Box 90-N)
      - Humphrey, Sen. Hubert H., 1974-1978 (Box 90-N)
      - Johnson, Lady Bird, 1971-1977 (Box 90-N)
      - Johnson, Mildred, 1967-1970 (Box 90-N)
      - Kauffman, Draper, 1981 (Box 90-N)
      - Kelley, Frank J., 1981 (Box 90-N)
      - King, Maria, 1974 (Box 90-N)
      - Leach, Elwin, 1977-1981 (Box 90-N)
      - Levin, Joseph (re. USSR trip), 1971 (Box 90-N)
      - Levin, Sander, 1968-1970 (Box 90-N)
      - Lindbergh, Charles A., 1969 (Box 90-N)
      - Locke, Hubert, 1967-1969 (Box 90-N)
      - Marcos, Ferdinand and Imelda, 1971-1973 (Box 90-N)
      - McCollough, Patrick, 1970 (Box 90-N)
      - McGhee, Bishop H. C., 1973-1985 (Box 90-N)
      - Middleton, Dr. John, 1971 (Box 90-N)
      - Monaghan & Co., 1970-1973 (Box 90-N)
      - Moody, Blair, Jr., 1973-1983 (Box 90-N)
      - Neal, Dr. Ernest, 1971 (Box 90-N)
      - Price, Hickman and Margaret, 1971-1979 (Box 90-N)
      - Riegel, Donald W., Jr., 1975-1982 (Box 90-N)
      - Rockefeller, Nelson A., 1973 (Box 90-N)
      - Rupe, Lyle, 1973 (Box 90-N)
      - Russell, Julie Lawler, 1966-1970 (Box 90-N)
      - Staebler, Neil, 1967-1983; 2 folders (Box 90-N)
      - Stanford, Richard E. (re. M. Price), 1969 (Box 90-N)
      - Steinbach, Dr. Albert, 1970 (Box 90-N)
      - Swan, William C., 1969-1970 (Box 90-N)
      - Tabueno family, 1968-1987 (Box 90-N)
      - Taylor, David, 1967-1969 (Box 90-N)
      - Vaughn, Ed, 1986 (Box 90-N)
      - Voelker, John, 1983-1985 (Box 90-N)
      - Warner, Dr. Robert, 1971-1985 (Box 90-N)
      - Warren, Dean Leslie G., 1972-1982 (Box 90-N)
      - Williams, Charles and Edna Stock, 1972-1977 (Box 90-N)
      - Williams, Richard, 1971-1984 (Box 90-N)
      - Wilson, James, 1977 (Box 90-N)
      - Woodfill, Stuart, 1975-1977 (Box 90-N)
    - Saint Paul's Cathedral Church, 1967-1988
      - Annual Meetings
        - 1970-1971 (Box 91-N)
        - 1979 (Box 91-N)
        - 1988 (Box 91-N)
      - Bylaws, n.d. (Box 91-N)
      - Committees, 1968-1979; 8 folders (Box 91-N)
      - Correspondence, 1967-1987; 3 folders (Box 91-N)
      - Dioceses of Michigan, 1967-1980; 3 folders (Box 91-N)
      - Financial Materials, 1968-1987; 9 folders (Box 91-N)
      - History of Trustees, 1967 (Box 91-N)
      - Sermons, 1969-1988
        - Allen, John, 1978 (Box 91-N)
        - Brunson, 1988 (Box 91-N)
        - Emrich, Richard, 1971-1985 (Box 91-N)
        - Herlong, Bertram, 1979-1986 (Box 91-N)
        - McLaren, 1971 (Box 91-N)
        - Warren, Dean Leslie, 1969-1978; 2 folders (Box 91-N)
      - Topical, 1967-1986; 9 folders (Box 91-N)
      - Vestry Meeting Minutes and Materials, 1967-1987; 52 folders (Box 92-N)
        (chronologically)
    - Schedules, 1961-1986
      - 1961-1966 (Box 93-N)
        (Includes Africa and Senate bid)
      - 1967-1970 (Box 94-N)
        (Includes Philippines and first run for Michigan Supreme Court)
      - 1971-1975 (Box 95-N)
        (Michigan Supreme Court)
      - 1976-1980 (Box 96-N)
        (Michigan Supreme Court and 1978 campaign for the court)
      - 1981-1986 (Box 97-N)
    - Speeches, 1961-1987
      - 1961-1966 (Box 98-N)
      - 1967-1971 (Box 99-N)
      - 1972-1979 (Box 100-N)
      - 1980-1987 (Box 101-N)
    - Topical files, 1971-1987
      - Africa, 1971-1979; 3 folders (Box 102-N)
      - African Art, 1971-1978 (Box 102-N)
      - Blanchard for Governor, 1982 (Box 102-N)
      - Blue Star Mothers of America, 1980-1986 (Box 102-N)
      - Coalition to End the Death Penalty, 1972-1977 (Box 102-N)
      - Council of Former Governors (H. Loveless), 1975-1979 (Box 102-N)
      - Cuttington College Crossroads, 1976 (Box 102-N)
      - Davis, Palmer, & Biggs, 1971-1979 (Box 102-N)
      - De Groot's "du Detroit", 1975 (Box 102-N)
      - Detroit Bank and Trust Co., 1971-1985 (Box 102-N)
      - Detroit Schools Cantorum, 1977 (Box 102-N)
      - Foreign Consular Offices in Detroit, 1976 (Box 102-N)
      - Grand Traverse Band of Ottawa and Chippewa ("Big Abe"), 1985-1986 (Box 102-N)
      - High Twelve Club, 1971 (Box 102-N)
      - History of the 1948 Campaign, Undated (Box 102-N)
      - National Center for Automated Information Retrieval, 1974 (Box 102-N)
      - National Society of the Sons of the American Revolution, 1972 (Box 102-N)
      - Natural Resources, 1972-1975 (Box 102-N)
      - Philippines, 1977-1986 (Box 102-N)
      - Political, 1972-1973 (Box 102-N)
      - Saint Paul's (Williams' Sunday school class), undated (Box 102-N)
      - Trips, 1972-1986; 6 folders (Box 102-N)
      - Universitie International, 1972-1975 (Box 102-N)
      - Wayne State University Self-Study Task Force, 1975 (Box 102-N)
      - Williams, G. Mennen, Conference memos, 1980 (Box 102-N)
    - Miscellaneous Personal Materials, 1948-1988
      - Genealogical files (including GMW's reflections), 1950s-1978; 7 folders (Box 102-N)
        (also includes 18th century lease and conveyance documents perhaps relating to members of the Williams family)
      - 1948 Election Histories (including GMW's reflections), 1970-1985; 7 folders (Box 103-N)
      - Michigan State University Presidency, 1969 (Box 103-N)
      - Oral History Transcript (GMW), 1970 (Box 103-N)
      - Leadership course for Oakland University, 1987-1988; 3 folders (Box 103-N)
      - Scrapbook on Africa, 1959-1961 (Box 103-N)
      - Clippings re Williams, 1948-1987; 3 folders (Box 103-N)
      - Stamp Collection, undated; 2 folders (Box 103-N)
      - First Day Covers, 1960s-1978; 1 box (Box 103-N)
    - Personal papers of Nancy Quirk Williams, 1928-1989
      - Correspondence, 1939-1968; 1987-1988; 59 folders (Box 104-N)
      - Condolences on GMW's death, 1988; 4 folders (Box 104-N)
      - Condolences on GMW's death, 1988; 6 folders (Box 105-N)
      - Diary, 1956 (Box 105-N)
      - Nursing and School Notes, 1931-1940s; 5 folders (Box 105-N)
      - Schedules (Senate campaign), 1966; 10 folders (Box 105-N)
      - Speech Drafts, 1946-1960; 3 folders (Box 105-N)
      - Trip Notes (Africa), 1961; 3 folders (Box 105-N)
      - Scrapbooks and Photo Albums, circa 1928-1988 (Box 106-N)
        - circa 1928-1939, 7 volumes (Box 106-N)
        - 1940-1988, 6 volumes (Box 107-N)
- Visual Materials
  The Visual Materials subgroup includes photographs, color transparencies, caricatures and drawings, films, and videotapes documenting all phases of Williams life and career, but with an emphasis on his years as governor and Undersecretary of State for African Affairs. Owing both to the way in which the collection was received and the manner in which it was initially processed, the visual materials were arranged and described separately from the paper records. The subgroup is arranged in series based on format.
  - Photographs
    The Photographs series is divided into subseries based on the different phases of Williams career that in may ways correspond to the arrangement of the paper records. The Principal photograph subseries include Family and Formal Portraits, Gubernatorial activities, Campaigns and Personalities, Assistant Secretary of State for African Affairs, Ambassador to the Philippines, and Post-1966. There is also a Miscellaneous subseries of framed photographs which are or have been on display in the library.
    - Family and Formal Portraits
      - Early Pictures, 2 folders (Box 1-P)
      - Williams with others as choir boy (Box 9-P)
      - Princeton University activities, 1933-1937 (Box 1-P)
      - Naval Activities (including U.S. naval carriers) (Box 1-P)
      - Parents (Box 1-P)
      - Richard Williams (brother) and family (Box 1-P)
      - Formal Portraits, 2 folders; includes tintype (Box 1-P)
      - Formal photographs (alone and with Nancy and family), 2 oversize folders (Box 9-P)
      - Formal photographs (Box 14-P)
        (outsize)
      - Formal Portraits, 1970s; 1980s (Box 1-P)
      - Office Portraits (Box 1-P)
      - Studio Prints (Box 1-P)
      - Miscellaneous Portraits (Box 1-P)
      - Informal Pictures, 2 folders (Box 1-P)
      - Informal Pictures (Box 9-P)
      - Informal Pictures, 1970s; 1980s (Box 1-P)
      - With Nancy Williams
        - Formal (Box 1-P)
        - Informal, 3 folders (Box 1-P)
      - Nancy Q. Williams
        - Early Pictures (Box 1-P)
        - College scrapbook, 1930-1934 (Box 9-P)
          (University of Michigan Class of 1937. Four loose pages.)
        - Portraits (Box 14-P)
        - Photocopy of scrapbook (Box 1-P)
        - Parents and family (Box 1-P)
        - Quirk-Trowbridge family (Box 1-P)
        - Formal Portraits, 2 folders (Box 1-P)
        - Formal Portraits (Box 9-P)
        - Wedding Photos (Box 1-P)
        - Wedding Photos (Box 9-P)
        - Informal Pictures, 3 folders (Box 1-P)
      - Formal Family Portraits 1970s, 1980s (including grandchildren), 1970-1989; 2 folders (Box 1-P)
      - Formal Family Portraits (color negatives) (Box 1-P)
      - Formal portraits of Richard Williams family and of mother (Box 9-P)